Guide to the Felix S. Cohen Papers Addition
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writing Projects, 1927-1960; Series III; 5.2; (6 boxes)
  - Lectures
    - "Philosophy of Values", 1931 (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - New School Legal Notes, 1931-1932 (Box 16, Folder 347)
    - Labor Legislation - General, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 348)
    - Labor, The Constitution and the Courts, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - Social Control of Capital, undated (Box 16, Folder 350)
    - Conference on Methods in Philosophy of the Sciences, undated (Box 16, Folder 351)
    - "Ethics and Morals of Our Foreign Policy", 1951 (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - The Legal Conscience (1960)
    - Correspondence and typescripts, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 354)
    - Source Material, circa 1960 (Box 16, Folder 355-357)
    - Source Material, I. Law and Ethics, circa 1960 (Box 16, Folder 358-363)
    - Source Material, II. The Indian's Quest for Justice, circa 1960 (Box 16, Folder 364-367)
    - Source Material, III. Studies in the Philosophy of American Democracy, circa 1960 (Box 17, Folder 368-375)
    - Editor's note and source material, circa 1960 (Box 17, Folder 376)
    - "The Aesthetic and Metaphysical Bases of the Conflict of Laws", circa 1960 (Box 17, Folder 377)
    - Flyer for book, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 378)
  - Writings by others
    - Writings by others, undated (Box 17, Folder 379-380)
  - Printed Material
    - Writings by Felix S. Cohen, circa 1930-1950 (Box 17, Folder 381-384)
    - "Felix S. Cohen: A Fighter for Justice", 1956 (Box 17, Folder 385)
    - A Jurisprudential Symposium in Memory of Felix S. Cohen, Rutgers Law Review, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 386)
- Organizational Affiliations, 1927-1954; Series IV; 7; (7 boxes)
  The Organization Affiliations series consists of material stemming from Cohen's participation and involvement with various social, political, and professional organizations. In particular, there are extensive files relating to Cohen's activities with the Socialist Party and the National Lawyer's Guild.
  The Organization Affiliations series is arranged into two subseries: Social and Political Organizations, and Legal Organizations.
  - Social and Political Organizations, 1927-1948
    This subseries largely consists of files relating to Cohen's involvement with the Socialist Party during the 1930s. Also found are files relating to his activities with the League for Industrial Democracy, the Alumni Committee on Academic Freedom at City College, the American Civil Liberties Union, and other social and political organizations. The files contain memoranda, correspondence, notes, report, minutes, publications, and other printed material.
    Files are arranged by organization with printed material arranged at the end.
    - Socialist Party, 1927-1945 (Box 18, Folder 387-406)
    - Socialist Party, 1927-1945 (Box 19, Folder 407-411)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1934-1954 (Box 19, Folder 412-420)
    - Committee on Militarism in Education, 1932-1940 (Box 19, Folder 421-422)
    - Alumni Committee on Academic Freedom, City College, 1932-1933 (Box 19, Folder 423-424)
    - Continental Congress of Workers and Farmers, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 425-426)
    - American Labor Associates, 1931-1933 (Box 20, Folder 427)
    - Corporate Research, undated (Box 20, Folder 428)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1933-1938 (Box 20, Folder 429)
    - Social Science Research Council, Report, undated (Box 20, Folder 430)
    - Industrial Research Group, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 431)
    - American Guardian, 1935-1939 (Box 20, Folder 432)
    - Miscellaneous Organizations and Lists, 1935-1941 (Box 20, Folder 433)
    - Washington Activities, 1934-1935 (Box 20, Folder 434-438)
    - Sharecroppers Relief Fund, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 439)
    - People's Lobby, 1934-1936 (Box 20, Folder 440-441)
    - American Foundation for Abundance, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 442-443)
    - Conference on Jewish Relations, 1938-1946 (Box 20, Folder 444-446)
    - Friends of Democracy, 1940-1944 (Box 20, Folder 447)
    - Consultative Council of Jewish Organizations, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 448)
    - Printed Material, undated (Box 20, Folder 449-456)
    - Printed Material, undated (Box 21, Folder 457-465)
  - Legal Organizations, 1936-1943
    This subseries consists of files relating primarily to Cohen's activities with the National Lawyers Guild, where he served on the International Law Committee and National Executive Committee, as well as some files relating to his work the Intitute of Living Law. The files contain reports, memoranda, correspondence, background material, publications, and other printed material.
    Files within the Legal Organizations subseries are arranged into two groupings: National Lawyers Guild and Institute of Living Law.
    More extensive documentation of Cohen's activities with the Institute of Living Law can found in the Felix S. Cohen Papers, WA MSS S-1325.
    - National Lawyers Guild
      - National Lawyers Guild, 1938-1939 (Box 21, Folder 466)
      - International Law Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 21, Folder 467-470)
      - Publications regarding international affairs, 1936, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 471)
      - "Current I. L. Committee Work", 1938 (Box 21, Folder 472)
      - "Current I. L. Committee Work", 1939 (Box 21, Folder 473)
      - D. C. Chapter, 1937-1939 (Box 21, Folder 474-475)
      - "Miscellaneous Guild Matters", 1937 (Box 22, Folder 476)
      - Quarterly and Newsletter, 1937-1939 (Box 22, Folder 477-479)
      - "F. S. C. Personal File", 1939 (Box 22, Folder 480)
      - Munitions Material, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 481)
      - Publicity Referendum, 1938-1939 (Box 22, Folder 482-483)
      - Correspondence regarding Spain and D. C., 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 484)
      - "F. S. C. Personal Correspondence", 1937-1939 (Box 22, Folder 485-486)
      - Comments on Spanish Report, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 487)
      - Membership, 1938-1939 (Box 22, Folder 488)
      - Referendum Results, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 489)
      - Law Students, 1937-1940 (Box 22, Folder 490)
      - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 491)
      - Anti-War Treaties and Neutrality Legislation, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 492)
      - Neutrality, circa 1939 (Box 22, Folder 493)
      - Collective Security, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 494)
      - Neutrality Legislation, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 495)
      - National Executive Committee Minutes, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 496)
      - Past Committee Reports, 1937-1939 (Box 23, Folder 497)
      - International Law Committee, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 498)
      - "Lawyers Guild - Letter of Resignation, etc.", 1940 (Box 23, Folder 499)
      - National Labor Relations Board, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 500)
      - Institute, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 501)
      - Guild Constituion, etc., 1939 (Box 23, Folder 502)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1939 (Box 23, Folder 503)
      - German Report and Supporting Documents, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 504-505)
      - Legal Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 23, Folder 506-507)
      - Anti-War Treaties Report, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 508)
      - Department of State Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 23, Folder 509)
      - Comments on Munitions Report, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 510)
      - "Guild (Pecord Resolution)", 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 511)
      - Neutrality Report, circa 1939 (Box 23, Folder 512)
      - Far Eastern Report, circa 1939 (Box 23, Folder 513)
      - Palestine Report, circa 1939 (Box 23, Folder 514)
      - Report Correspondence, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 515)
      - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 516)
      - Munitions Report, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 517-519)
      - Copies of various reports, 1938-1939 (Box 24, Folder 520)
      - Resolutions, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 521)
      - "Rus-Fin Res", 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 522-526)
      - German Report, Editorial Corrections, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 527)
      - National Committee Reports, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 528-530)
      - Minutes, Membership Reports, etc., 1937-1939 (Box 24, Folder 531-532)
      - Referendum, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 533-534)
    - Institute of Living Law, 1941-1943 (Box 24, Folder 535-540)
- Personal Papers, circa 1920-1960; Series V; 4.21; (5 boxes)
  The Personal Papers series consists of Cohen's student papers, family scrapbooks, photographs, reel-to-reel tapes, other papers, and some papers of Lucy Kramer Cohen, documenting more personal aspects of Cohen's life.
  Material is arranged largely by format.
  - Student Papers
    Arranged in rough chronological order
    - English 4-C Composition Books, circa 1920 (Box 25, Folder 541-542)
    - Spanish Lessons, circa 1920 (Box 25, Folder 543)
    - City College, 1925 (Box 25, Folder 544-549)
    - City College, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 550)
    - Clippings, 1925-1926 (Box 25, Folder 551-552)
    - College Essay on Labor History, 1927 (Box 25, Folder 553)
    - Miscellaneous school papers, 1925-1927 (Box 25, Folder 554-555)
    - Campus and Military Science, circa 1927 (Box 25, Folder 556)
    - H. S. Math Exam, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 557)
    - Fraternity, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 558)
    - Law School Notebooks, circa 1930 (Box 25, Folder 559-560)
    - Law School Notebooks, circa 1930 (Box 26, Folder 561-568)
    - Law School Texts, circa 1930 (Box 26, Folder 569-570)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 26, Folder 571-590)
  - Family Scrapbooks, undated (Box 27, Folder 591)
    See also Family Scrapbook (from Series V)
  - Letters, Photographs, undated (Box 27, Folder 592)
  - Wedding telegrams, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 593)
  - Letters, undated (Box 27, Folder 594)
  - Resorts, undated (Box 27, Folder 595)
  - Hedonist Hymnbook, undated (Box 27, Folder 596)
  - Capitol City Forum, undated (Box 27, Folder 597)
  - Clippings from Yiddish newspapers, undated (Box 27, Folder 598)
  - Clipping, Article on Felix S. Cohen in City College Campus Paper, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 599)
  - Draft of Resignation Letter from Solicitor's Office and Clipping, circa 1948 (Box 27, Folder 600)
  - Birth certificate of Karen Cohen (copy), undated (Box 27, Folder 601)
  - Death certificate of Felix S. Cohen (copy), undated (Box 27, Folder 602)
  - Maps and pamphlets, undated (Box 27, Folder 603-605)
  - Other Papers, undated (Box 27, Folder 606-613)
  - Felix S. Cohen Fund Committee, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 614-616)
  - Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers, undated (Box 28, Folder 617-634)
  - Reel-to-reel tapes
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Reference copies are available and filed in the folders.
    - Felix S. Cohen Service, Washington, D.C., 1953 October 21; 1 (Box 29, Folder 635)
    - Memorial Meeting for Felix S. Cohen, 1953 December 4 (Box 29, Folder 636)
    - "Truman CCNX", undated (Box 29, Folder 637)
- Oversize, 0.25; (1 box)
  - Family Scrapbook (from Series V), undated (Box 30 (Oversize), Folder 638)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Felix S. Cohen Service, Washington, D.C., 1953 October 21; 1; 00:22:48; A high amount of hum and high background noise can be heard on the audiotape reel. The program is distorted at times. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002099368566)
  - Memorial Meeting for Felix S. Cohen, 1953 December 4; 1; 00:32:47 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002099368574)
  - "Truman CCNX", undated; 1; 00:03:29; The program ends abruptly. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002099368582)